<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amanda&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amanda&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DC R Conference Recap</title>
      <link>/2019/11/12/dcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/12/dcr/</guid>
      <description>The overview: DC R 2019, hosted by Lander Analytics, was held Nov 7-9 at Georgtown University. The short, but action-packed, conference consisted of one day of workshops and two days of talks. Find the videos on DC R website (available soon) and associated tweets via the #rstatsdc hashtag on Twitter. Also, see Jared Lander’s blog post for a higher level overview of the conference (with lots of fun pics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>classification</title>
      <link>/2019/10/07/classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/07/classification/</guid>
      <description>## ── Attaching packages ────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 3.2.1 ✔ purrr 0.3.3 ## ✔ tibble 2.1.3 ✔ dplyr 0.8.3 ## ✔ tidyr 1.0.0 ✔ stringr 1.4.0 ## ✔ readr 1.1.1 ✔ forcats 0.3.0 ## ── Conflicts ───────────────────────────────── tidyverse_conflicts() ── ## ✖ dplyr::filter() masks stats::filter() ## ✖ dplyr::lag() masks stats::lag() ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;magrittr&amp;#39; ## The following object is masked from &amp;#39;package:purrr&amp;#39;: ## ## set_names ## The following object is masked from &amp;#39;package:tidyr&amp;#39;: ## ## extract ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;rtweet&amp;#39; ## The following object is masked from &amp;#39;package:purrr&amp;#39;: ## ## flatten ## here() starts at /home/rstudio/AmandaRP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny App: Twitter Likes</title>
      <link>/2019/08/02/rstats-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/02/rstats-love/</guid>
      <description>I love that Twitter recently came out with bookmarks! My previous MO on Twitter was to ❤️ posts that contain information that I want to keep for later, most of which are #rstats tweets. I now have 700+ likes, which are time consuming to browse through when I need to find something. I didn’t find an easy way to search likes within Twitter itself, so I built a shiny app to do that using the rtweet and shiny R packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis of Psalms</title>
      <link>/2019/06/22/text-analysis-of-psalms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/22/text-analysis-of-psalms/</guid>
      <description>Psalms is a book in both the Christian Bible and the Jewish Tanakh. I thought it would be interesting to look at a sentiment analysis of the book. I chose to work with the “Good News Translation” of the bible as it does not have copyright issues like some of the other translations (per the American Bible Society). We’ll use the tidytext and sentimentr R packages to do the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the hddtest R package</title>
      <link>/2019/05/24/new-r-package-hddtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/24/new-r-package-hddtest/</guid>
      <description>I’d like to introduce a package that I wrote recently, hddtest, for two sample hypothesis testing of high dimensional discrete data. The package is currently available on GitHub. It contains methods for both multivariate binary data and multinomial data.
I’ll illustrate the use of one of its functions, the multinomial neighborhood test, by using a dataset included in hddtest called twoNewsGroups. It contains document term frequency matrices for two of the 20 newgroups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Bingo</title>
      <link>/2019/03/10/stats-bingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/10/stats-bingo/</guid>
      <description>I just wrapped up another round of teaching stats. I co-teach two courses per year as an adjunct instructor: one class that covers intro stats and the other that hits higher level concepts. Both courses move at a high pace; they’re intended to be a survey course for professionals with a STEM background. Some students have a math background, but have never taken a statistics course. Other students have had statistics a long time ago in their undergraduate studies, but want to brush up on the material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog site, created with the R blogdown package! I&amp;rsquo;m a statistician based in the Washington DC metro area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rstudio::conf recap</title>
      <link>/2019/01/26/rstudio-conf-2019-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/26/rstudio-conf-2019-recap/</guid>
      <description>The overview: I had the pleasure of attending rstudio::conf 2019 (in Austin, TX), a conference about all things R and RStudio. Over 1700 people attended the main conference, which consisted of three tracks (so my notes below cover only a third of the conference talks). There were an additional two days of tutorials and a two-day hackathon, which I did not attend. The 2020 conference will be in San Francisco Jan 27-30.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>