<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Amanda&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Amanda&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanda.rbind.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What exactly are we testig? A closer look at the train/test split</title>
      <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/2020/11/08/what-exactly-are-we-testig-a-closer-look-at-the-train-test-split/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda.rbind.io/2020/11/08/what-exactly-are-we-testig-a-closer-look-at-the-train-test-split/</guid>
      <description>In the paper Are We Really Making Much Progress? A Worrying Analysis of Recent Neural Recommendation Approaches, authors Dacrema, Cremonesi, and Jannach evaluate various neural networks which were designed for recommendation systems and proposed in prominent machine learning journals. A recommendation system is an information filtering system which uses user history (e.g. purchases, page views, clicks, thumbs up/down, etc) to provide personalized item recommendations to users.
The authors point out a few mistakes or “questionable techniques” used in the research they were attempting to reproduce and evaluate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny R-Ladies</title>
      <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/2020/02/07/shiny-r-ladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda.rbind.io/2020/02/07/shiny-r-ladies/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year I had the pleasure of talking about R shiny at the Baltimore R-Ladies Meetup. shiny is an R package for building interactive web applications.
We made an app showing the wildfires in south eastern Australia along with historic rainfall and temperature data. This dataset was provided as a Tidy Tuesday dataset by the R for Data Science Learning Community.
Here is a peak at the app…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DC R Conference Recap</title>
      <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/11/12/dcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/11/12/dcr/</guid>
      <description>The overview: DC R 2019, hosted by Lander Analytics, was held Nov 7-9 at Georgtown University. The short action-packed conference consisted of one-day workshops and two days of talks. Find the videos on the DC R website (available soon) and associated tweets via the #rstatsdc hashtag on Twitter. Also, see Jared Lander’s blog post for a higher level overview of the conference with lots of fun pics.
Highlights for me personally included Malorie Hughes’ presentation of flexdashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny App: Twitter Likes</title>
      <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/08/02/rstats-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/08/02/rstats-love/</guid>
      <description>I love that Twitter recently came out with bookmarks! My previous MO on Twitter was to ❤️ posts that contain information that I want to keep for later, most of which are #rstats tweets. I now have 700+ likes, which are time consuming to browse through when I need to find something. I didn’t find an easy way to search likes within Twitter itself, so I built a shiny app to do that using the rtweet and shiny R packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis of Psalms</title>
      <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/06/22/text-analysis-of-psalms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/06/22/text-analysis-of-psalms/</guid>
      <description>Psalms is a book in both the Christian Bible and the Jewish Tanakh. I thought it would be interesting to look at a sentiment analysis of the book. I chose to work with the “Good News Translation” of the bible as it does not have copyright issues like some of the other translations (per the American Bible Society). We’ll use the tidytext and sentimentr R packages to do the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the hddtest R package</title>
      <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/05/24/new-r-package-hddtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/05/24/new-r-package-hddtest/</guid>
      <description>I’d like to introduce a package that I wrote recently, hddtest, for two sample hypothesis testing of high dimensional discrete data. The package is currently available on GitHub. It contains methods for both multivariate binary data and multinomial data.
I’ll illustrate the use of one of its functions, the multinomial neighborhood test, by using a dataset included in hddtest called twoNewsGroups. It contains document term frequency matrices for two of the 20 newgroups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Bingo</title>
      <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/03/10/stats-bingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/03/10/stats-bingo/</guid>
      <description>I just wrapped up another round of teaching stats. I co-teach two courses per year as an adjunct instructor: one class that covers intro stats and the other that hits higher level concepts. Both courses move at a high pace; they’re intended to be a survey course for professionals with a STEM background. Some students have a math background, but have never taken a statistics course. Other students have had statistics a long time ago in their undergraduate studies, but want to brush up on the material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rstudio::conf recap</title>
      <link>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/01/26/rstudio-conf-2019-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda.rbind.io/2019/01/26/rstudio-conf-2019-recap/</guid>
      <description>The overview: I had the pleasure of attending rstudio::conf 2019 (in Austin, TX), a conference about all things R and RStudio. Over 1700 people attended the main conference, which consisted of three tracks (so my notes below cover only a third of the conference talks). There were an additional two days of tutorials and a two-day hackathon, which I did not attend. The 2020 conference will be in San Francisco Jan 27-30.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
